Today I would be talking about how to tack up a horse.
Next we would be putting on the saddle pad and the back pad.
Not everyone uses a back pad and we would start with just the saddle pad.
So you know that the front is a front cause it has a strap for the girth to go through and a strap that attaches to the gullet of the saddle.
So we are going to put this on and it should come up to half of his withers, in the middle of his withers.
There is a 2 example of basic back pads; it is just a fleece general supporting protecting pad.
This is for raising up the back of your saddle to give it a better fit.
So today we are just going to use this basic fleece back pad.
You just want to line it up so that the back pad does not go any further then the saddle pad and that it is lined up evenly with this side.
So it is even on both sides of his back.